Get ready to run.
The Maze Runner is a action, mystery, science fiction film directed by Wes Ball.
A teenager with no memory of his past finds himself among a group of boys living
in a walled enclosure surrounded by a massive, ever-changing maze.
As he struggles to adapt to their rules and society, he begins to uncover clues
that may lead to escape and the truth behind their confinement.
Thomas, played by Dylan O'Brien.
Teresa Agnes, played by Kaya Scodelario.
Newt, played by Thomas Brodie-Sangster.
Minho, played by Ki Hong Lee.
Gally, played by Will Poulter.
Alby, played by Aml Ameen.
The Maze Runner is a 2014 American dystopian science fiction film directed by Wes Ball,
in his feature directorial debut, based on James Dashner's 2009 novel.
It is the first installment in The Maze Runner film series and was
produced by Noah Oppenheim, Grant Pierce Myers and T.
The film stars Dylan O'Brien, Kaya Scodelario, Thomas
Brodie-Sangster, Will Poulter and Patricia Clarkson.
The story follows sixteen-year-old Thomas, portrayed by O'Brien, who awakens in a rusty elevator with no memory of who he is, only to learn that he has been delivered to the middle of an intricate
maze, along with many other boys, who have been trying to find their way out of the ever-changing labyrinth—all while establishing a functioning society in what they call the Glade.
Development of The Maze Runner began in January 2011 when Fox purchased the film rights to Dashner's novel with
Gotham Group and Temple Hill Entertainment as producers and Catherine Hardwicke intended to direct.
In 2012, Ball was hired to direct the film adaptation after presenting an animated short film titled
Ruin with a similar tone and was initially considered for a feature-length adaptation.
Principal photography began in Baton Rouge, Louisiana on May 13,
2013, and officially concluded on July 12, 2013.
The Maze Runner was released on September 19, 2014, in
the United States by 20th Century Fox.
The film received positive reviews, with praise for Ball's
direction, the actors' performances and the film's tone.
Critics considered it to be better than most young
adult book-to-film adaptations.
The film was first at the box office in its opening weekend, grossing $32.5
million, making it the seventh-highest-grossing debut in September.
The film earned over $348 million worldwide at the box
office, against its budget of $34 million.
Two sequels, Maze Runner: The Scorch Trials and Maze Runner:
The Death Cure, were released in 2015 and 2018.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, escape,
dystopia, maze, post-apocalyptic future.
The tone is intense and thought_provoking and mind_bending.